<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Nathan's Blog</title><link>/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Nathan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 18:38:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Get the First N Bytes of a File</title><link>/2020/04/14/how-to-get-the-first-n-bytes-of-a-file/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/14/how-to-get-the-first-n-bytes-of-a-file/</guid><description>There comes a time when you just need to take a little off the top of a file, see what you are working with. That is where knowing how to use a utility like &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/head.1.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt;head&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; can help. Just running:
Will get you
http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/head.1.htmlBut what if that file does not have nice lines? Large SQL dump files come to mind. head has an answer. Use the -c flag to print the beginning bytes of a file instead of lines.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Windows Subsystem for Linux and SSH</title><link>/2020/01/16/setting-up-windows-subsystem-for-linux-to-ssh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 21:51:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/16/setting-up-windows-subsystem-for-linux-to-ssh/</guid><description>The Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) is one of the best features on Windows 10. It makes development so much easier than it used to be but still has a few hiccups. Kinda like Linux, some things don’t “just work.” One pesky thing that I recently dealt with was getting SSH to work with a keypair file from WSL. Here is how to get SSH working on WSL.
Goal Given a keypair file, we want to invoke ssh from the command line and establish a tunnel to another server.</description></item><item><title>Kafkacat Amazon Workspace</title><link>/2020/01/14/kafkacat-amazon-workspace/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/14/kafkacat-amazon-workspace/</guid><description>Below are some notes on getting &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/edenhill/kafkacat#build&amp;quot;&amp;gt;kafkacat&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; installed on an Amazon workspace with admin access.
The commands listed on the GitHub page will not work without a little preparation. A Linux Amazon Workspace image is based on Amazon Linux. Attempts to use a package manager like yum go through a plugin, amzn_workspaces_filter_updates. This filter only has a handful of packages (30 at the time of this writing) that can be pulled.</description></item></channel></rss>