<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Concepts on Nathan's Blog</title><link>/categories/Concepts/</link><description>Recent content in Concepts on Nathan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 21:08:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/Concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Logic for Artificial Intelligence</title><link>/2018/10/18/logic-for-artificial-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 21:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/10/18/logic-for-artificial-intelligence/</guid><description>Patrick Winston, Artificial Intelligence, pp 283Logic in artificial intelligence can be used to help an agent create rules of inference. It provides a formal framework for creating if-then statements. Formal logic statements can be difficult for beginners because of the symbols and vocabulary used. Below is a cheat sheet for some of the basic symbols and definitions.
&amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Definition &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Logical conjunction. In most instances it will be used as an AND operator.</description></item><item><title>Qualia</title><link>/2018/10/10/qualia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 03:36:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/10/10/qualia/</guid><description>Have you ever tried to describe the color red to someone who suffers from protanopia, deuteranopia, protanomaly, or deuteranomaly? It is nearly impossible since those who are red-green color blind are missing the corresponding photoreceptors. The experience of seeing red is so familiar to those who have experienced it. And that type of experience, one which is difficult to communicate, does not change based on other experiences, is unique to the individual experiencing it, and immediately recognized, is qualia.</description></item><item><title>A Brief Introduction to Bayes&amp;#8217; Theorem</title><link>/2018/08/22/a-brief-introduction-to-bayes-theorem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 13:13:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/08/22/a-brief-introduction-to-bayes-theorem/</guid><description>Bayes’ Theorem stated is, “the conditional probability of A given B is the conditional probability of B given A scaled by the relative probability of A compared to B”. I find it easier to understand through a practical explanation. Let’s say you are having a medical test performed at the recommendation of your doctor, who recommends tests to everyone because they get a nice kickback and college tuition is not cheap!</description></item></channel></rss>