<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on Nathan's Blog</title><link>nmaynes.github.io/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on Nathan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 07:54:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="nmaynes.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamically Set ORM Schemas via Sqlalchemy</title><link>nmaynes.github.io/post/2021-04-03-dynamically-set-schemas-sqlalchemy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 07:54:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>nmaynes.github.io/post/2021-04-03-dynamically-set-schemas-sqlalchemy/</guid><description>Sometimes the solution to a problem is so obvious, it takes a while to figure it out. I recently stumbled on such a problem when trying to configure a set of Object Relational Mappings (ORM) to support an application with the same set of table objects across different schemas in Postgres. Developing an ORM to support this pattern, a multi-tenant database model, proved challenging because of where I started. Below, I will detail the correct way to support the multi-tenant pattern as well as various approaches I came across and why they should not be used.</description></item><item><title>A Primer on Data Normalization</title><link>nmaynes.github.io/2020/11/29/a-primer-on-data-normalization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>nmaynes.github.io/2020/11/29/a-primer-on-data-normalization/</guid><description>Normalizing data is a common data engineering task. It prepares information to be stored in a way that minimizes duplication and is digestible by machines. It also aims to solve other problems and issues that are out of scope for this particular article but worth reading about if you find yourself struggling to understand jokes about E. F. Codd. This begs the question, why does normalization matter when entering information in a table or organizing a spreadsheet?</description></item></channel></rss>